NO ANIMALS WERE HARMED DURING
THE FILMING OF THIS PRODUCTION
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
Oh Kayıs!
Do you testify...
... that I fulfilled my task properly?
Yes, our Bey!
Oh Kayıs!
Do you accept...
... my title as a Bey?
Yes, our Bey!
Yes, my Bey.
If I announce my successor now...
... will you accept him like you have
accepted me?
And obey his every command?
We will, our Bey!
We will, our Bey.
My successor...
... to whom shall I leave my title
faithfully.
Your new Kayı Bey...
... who will fight in the path of Allah...
... who will carry the flag of Kayı from
victories to victories...
... who will never accept bondage...
... my son...
-My Bey!
-Father!
Father!
ONE DAY AGO
I don't think that way.
Because Osman and Yalvak Arslan left to
raid a base of Geyhatu.
They won't make it alive for sure.
Also, if the poison I sent to Kayı Bey
worked, it means the Tent is now derelict.
So there is chaos in the Tent right now.
Yes.
Yes, for sure there is.
I like cleaning.
Once the news comes, we will attack them
from every corner.
Are we going to attack Kulacahisar?
Are you really asking that?
Let me tell you something.
How long Kulacahisar resist when I kill
every Kayı?
Huh?
You're not underestimating my mind, right?
All we need to think about right now is
the raid of Tent.
We need to attack without thinking about
the amount of soldiers we might lose.
We won't leave any single Kayı alive!
It means we will butcher them all.
There you are!
Come here!
Come and give the good news!
Osman...
Osman?
... has returned to Kayı Tent with
his Alp.
Osman?
He returned where?
To Kayı Tent, sir.
Perfect!
Didn't he leave to raid the base of
Geyhatu?
How did he make it alive from there?
Yalvak Arslan?
He is alive as well, sir.
He is also on his way to Tent.
Knell down.
Knell down!
Geyhatu.
His base.
Raid.
Osman.
Okay.
Alright! Shut up!
Shut your mouth!
Alright.
Alright!
Shut up already!
Okay.
Geyhatu must have left before they even
went there.
Yes.
Geyhatu left before them.
The job fell to our lot, Flatyos.
The job fell to our lot.
Osman didn't die.
Instead, he returned to the Tent.
So, it means when we raid the Tent...
... Osman is going to greet us.
Well...
... if the poison I gave to Targun had
worked...
... so if their Kayı Bey died...
... there will still be chaos at the Tent.
There will be, right?
I'm sure they will blame Osman for
everything.
They will, right?
Naturaly...
... Mighty Caesar says that he doesn't
know Targun.
Anyways, my beloved friend...
... we will visit Targun and learn it
ourselves.
Let's see if their Kayı Bey is still
alive like Osman...
... or he is dead as to the poison.
What's my duty, Nikola?
Your duty?
You will prepare yourself, Flatyos.
I have a feeling in my guts that we will
take place in a bloody war today.
Do you mean this?
It's just a statue, Flatyos.
It can't talk.
Father.
Thanks to my Rab.
After seeing you like this, I will never
complain about something.
Inshallah, things are going to get better,
Selcen Hatun.
Thanks to my Rab.
Hatuns!
Let's leave.
Perhaps, Beys have things to talk about.
Bamsı.
My Bey.
I knew what you were up to all along.
Brother.
You...
... you were unconscious.
A Bey never leaves his Tent before he
hands the fiduciary.
Mind and heart work together.
And heart works for the best of people.
I heard everything and things happened
in the way I predicted them to.
So, after all, you want to become the Bey.
You might want to...
... but why would Allah want you to become
the Bey?
Dündar Bey.
What could Allah want from a Bey?
To continue his laws, my Bey.
You are right.
After all, Beyhood is supported by
Allah's laws.
Tell me, Gündüz.
Who preserves the Laws?
The Bey who gets his title from Allah.
Yes indeed.
The better the Laws are preserved,
the better a Bey's administration will be.
Now, it's your turn Savcı.
What happens when the Laws are spoiled.
There will be no unity in the universe,
my Bey.
It's the Laws what sustain the sky.
It's true.
Now, tell me, Osman.
How can the administration be handed from
one Bey to another?
The Bey is the Sun of Laws.
And a son of the Bey is a moon enlightened
by that very sun.
Oh, the Sun of Kayıs!
Whomever your light enlightens...
... and forms a full moon with your
light...
... will be the successor of you.
This is how your administration...
... gets handed to your successor.
It's true.
This is exactly how the administration
changes from one Bey to another.
My sons and my brother shall excuse us
now.
I need to consult my comrades.
In the meantime, you can think of an
explanation.
Who shall be the new Bey of Kayıs?
My son.
Targun Hatun.
Tell me whatever you need to tell here.
Go on.
The poison Nikola gave me...
... with this he asked me to poison the
Beys of Kayı.
What are you talking about?
Of course, I wasn't going to.
But he wants to meet me in order to learn
whether I did or not.
What did you just say?
May you stop, aunt.
Bala.
Nikola, huh?
It's unfair to keep Nikola waiting.
You shall go to him now.
Tell him you couldn't poison the Beys of
Kayı and that you have better plan.
Listen to me carefully.
It's clear what he is talking about with
Bamsı and Abdurrahman Bey.
Yes, it is.
He will consult them and his comrades
about the new Bey of Kayı.
And their choice is obvious.
It's also clear who you want, right
brother?
Yes, it is.
It's very clear.
What are you up to this time, Osman?
There is always something to do, brother.
Do I have your permission, my Bey?
Come in.
My Bey is waiting for you.
The day of salvation is close, father.
You will become free once again.
Then, we will take our revenge from
everyone.
And Osman will be mine.
Let' go!
Did you raid the base of Geyhatu
with Yalvak Arslan?
Yes, father.
It's true.
We thought it'd be better to attack before
they drew their swords against Turks.
And then?
He wasn't there.
We killed his soldiers and left.
Geyhatu once came to our Tent, my Bey.
And he might again.
Maintaining peace with Geyhatu is similar
to being friends with a bear.
And my Osman went to the inn of that bear
to kill it.
However, the bear wasn't there.
How about Yalvak Arslan?
How can you still trust him after
everything he has done?
I wasn't tricked by his pledges like the
others.
I looked him in the eyes...
... and saw the hopes about the future of
all Turks.
My nephew.
You are the one who told us not to
believe him.
How could you believe him by looking
him in the eyes?
Huh?
What kind of an assurance is this?
Uncle!
It's our own benefits that entrap us.
No one can trick someone who doesn't have
anything to lose.
Now, tell us, Savcı.
What's up with you and Osman?
You made me the Head Alp, my Bey.
Yet, he never acknowledged this choice of
yours.
He never thought of me as the Head Alp.
He thinks we are too eager to be trapped.
He thinks that we are slaves who don't
want to be free.
And he goes after an impossible autonomy.
Do you have anything to add, brother?
Isn't there a hope for autonomy?
Those who made us and Mongols enemies
are the ones who lost at Kösedağ war.
Kayı can't make the Turks autonomous all
by itself.
This will bring the end of Kayıs.
Thus, all Turks will lose their hope
eventually.
Do you agree with your brother and uncle?
Anything can be an illusion if we believe
so.
Once we start our own path in the name of
Allah as well as faith and effort...
... only then our dreams will come true.
Even Çobanoğulları belive in this dream
and fight against Geyhatu by themselves.
But, the most noble sons of Oğuz Kağan
are just watching them.
Is this proper?
Is this who we really are?
Tell me!
Let's say Çobanoğulları wants to meet
their death.
Would you want your Tent to end up in the
same way?
I'm the son of Ertuğrul Gazi.
I don't put my Tent into
a war they will lose.
But...
If death is inevitable,
and the end of this battle is testimony...
Then...
I'll run into testimony with my valiants
who dedicated their lives for our cause!
My creator gave me one last
chance to see my Tents state...
... and to declare my will.
Put your differences aside
and unite!
We need to take care of Nikola before
Geyhatu returns from tabriz.
After that...
... we'll choose a new Bey
everyone will unite under.
A Bey shines out
in such harsh times.
Your attitudes will determine
which one of you will be the Bey.
All men will see the new Bey.
Know that those who are separated
will be left desperate!
Now. What shall we do
to take down that infidel Nikola?
Talk!
That man came to life.
How does this happen, Lena?
What if he announces the Bey?
What if he chooses Osman?
Lena? What is it?
How are you this relaxed?
Don’t you think about what will happen
if he chooses Osman instead of Savcı?
It seems like you want Savcı to
be the Bey more than me, Hazal Hatun.
Thanks to Allah, Ertuğrul Bey
is back on his feet again.
What are they up to this time?
It’s hard to wait, isn’t it, Hatuns?
What is it, Selcan Hatun? You look
like you received some good news.
Did someone tell you something?
Yes. Ertuğrul Bey
told me before anyone else.
While Osman and Savcı
are fighting over it…
… I’ll choose my brother
Dündar who thinks he’ll be the Bey.
I’ll add something to that.
Those who team up for their own benefits…
… separate swiftly.
What I’m saying is,
watch out for each other.
Or you’ll be separated soon, Allah forbid.
Patience…
Tell me, son.
Which path should the Kayıs follow?
We need to enter
the infidels’ den, my Bey.
I say we gather all
the Alps and march to İnegöl.
What do you say, Dündar?
My Bey. Since
the snake’s head is in İnegöl…
… we shall go there and cut it.
Let’s siege İnegöl first.
Because if we kick Nikola out of there,
he won’t have a place to hold on to.
I think Osman is glad to hear that.
I do not agree.
I say I don’t want any
disagreements and you oppose everyone.
Do we give up on
the truth if everyone opposes it?
What is that truth?
What is on your mind?
If we siege İnegöl Fortress
now, we’ll lose too many men.
We need to ambush
Nikola’s soldiers and weaken him.
How will you accomplish that?
Nikola thinks that
Targun Hatun is still his spy.
He gets the news from her.
He trusts her more since
he heard that she’ll marry me.
He’ll listen to every word she says.
My tricks are ready.
Targun Hatun is probably
already on her way.
What is that trick?
What did you do, Cuman Girl?
Did you poison Kayı’s Beys?
Did you kill all of them?
They are all alive.
What did I tell you?
Should I slit your throat right here?
Tell me.
Come on.
Savcı Bey is trying
to be the Bey by force.
Osman Bey stood in his way.
Ertuğrul Bey all of a sudden stood
up and gathered everyone in a meeting.
When was I supposed
to poison them, Nikola?
How was I supposed to poison
those who always fight and never eat?
Did Ertuğrul Bey stood up?
Yes. But he’s still in bad condition.
Everyone is with him in the Tent.
And I came here.
Just as they were about to fight each
other, Ertuğrul Bey stood up. Is that it?
And now are they sitting and talking?
Flatyos! Is that God
of your on the Turks’ side?
God is with those who
follow the path of Jesus Christ.
Do you have anything
useful to say, Cuman Girl?
Yes, I do.
I told Osman Bey that I won’t
be marrying him before saving my father.
So, he’s now preparing to save my father.
How is Osman going to
save your father? Will he attack İnegöl?
How will he do that?
I played the trick instead
of you this time, Nikola.
You. tricks. Did you?
What kind of a trick are
you playing, Cuman girl?
Targun Hatun will convince Nikola
to bring her father to Kurtboğazı[İnegöl].
Are you sure Nikola
will take this bait, brother?
He won’t, brother. But he won’t
care because I’ll be there.
Instead of İnegöl’s walls,
we’ll battle Nikola’s men.
This is how we defeat Nikola.
Not a fortress battle,
but a battle of tricks.
And an opportunity for you
to work together. What do you say?
Even if it looks dangerous
if that’s what our father wants…
… that’s how it will move.
Since the orders come from
our Bey, all we can do is to obey.
Don’t worry, father.
We’ll do everything necessary.
Osman.
Start the preparations.
We start tomorrow.
As you wish, my Bey.
I’ll tell Osman Bey that you’ll
take my father to Kurtboğazı.
What if he doesn’t believe you?
Looks like you don’t
know me yet, Flatyos.
I’ll bring Osman Bey to
Kurtboğazı and you’ll bring my father.
The rest is yours.
I’ll leave with my father…
… and will never see
your evil faces again.
Not bad, Cuman girl.
Not bad at all.
Targun Hatun. We’ll bring
your father to Kurtboğazı. And…
… after one little
mistake, your father will die.
So will you.
Now go. Don’t make
future husband worried.
What do you say, Flatyos?
I think this is a trap, Nikola.
Maybe. But this is
still a really good opportunity.
We’ll take precautions.
We’ll act like they are setting up a trap.
Then, Flatyos, we’ll
win the war.
First, Ertuğrul Bey
got up from his death bed.
Then, this ambush thing.
I worry about you.
At least my father
didn’t ask about yesterday.
Otherwise neither Osman
nor I would have got what we wanted.
Out of the blue, we would
be the same as Gündüz and Dündar.
You say out of the blue. But you don’t
think that this could be Dündar’s plan.
You say that you won’t give up.
May Allah give you strength.
Uncle. Is our
agreement still valid?
Sure it is, my nephew.
This ambition makes brothers
fight each other, Lena.
Why would my Uncle stay away?
He also has a plan for sure.
I have some good news for you.
Bayhoca is on his way.
He’ll be in the Tent shortly.
My dear son!
I missed him so much.
I can’t wait to hug him!
I also missed him a lot.
Everything will be as
we wish, my Savcı.
Inshallah.
Osman Bey…
Everything started as a
trick, continued as a trick.
Are you that Osman Bey
whom they are afraid of?
I am. From now on,
you’re safe with us.
I was in it to save my father.
But I can’t even save myself now.
I’m a prisoner
of your eyes.
I fell prey to your strong arms.
What will I do know?
I’m eating my heart out.
Now you’re in
Bala’s arms, Osman Bey.
And I’m in pain.
Oh, Osman Bey…
I can’t stand it.
Look at you!
Look at these beautiful eyes.
One day, I’ll be held
responsible for these eyes.
It’s been a while since
you talked about my eyes.
My Bala…
Since my father has
fallen ill, I can’t see anything.
But now he’s up and ready for battle.
I regenerated, my Bala.
Is it just the eyes?
What about these hairs?
A planet for each curl,
a city for each strand…
My Osman…
I pray for a child.
I want it to be from me,
not from another Hatun.
Me too, my Bala.
I also pray for it.
I want you to give
me a successor.
I want my children
to have your noble spirit.
In them, I want to see a Kayı Bey’s
ambition for battle, and your clean heart.
My Bala…
Let’s pray.
Let’s call upon our Allah who
wants us to pray for everything.
May I enter, my Bey?
Targun Hatun?
What is it, Targun Hatun?
Bismillahirrahmanirrahim
[In the name of Allah, the merciful, the compassionate]
My Allah...
I'm coming to you.
You invite me to reunite
and let go.
Accept me to your Heaven which
my Halime wanders around in.
Make me reach my martyr brothers...
... my father Süleiman Şah...
... my mother Hayme Hatun.
Keep my Tent safe.
Protect it.
I came to say this...
I...
Uhm...
Thank you for what you
did for my father, Osman Bey.
I can't forget
what you did for me.
I came to say these.
Targun Hatun. Thank me after
I save your father tomorrow.
You're right, my Bey.
It's a little eary.
Actually, it's a little late!
I mean, I came at a late hour.
I should leave.
- Good night to you.
- Good night.
My Kayı Tent...
My mighty Tent...
Me ancestor Süleiman Şah...
My mother Hayme mother...
My Hatun...
My sweet Halime...
My brother Gündoğdu...
my brother Sungurtekin...
My brother Dündar...
Second mother to my children,
Selcan Hatun...
My brave Valiants...
Turgut, Bamsı, Abdurrahman, Doğan...
My children...
Gündüz, Savcı, my Osman...
My saint people...
Give me your blessings.
My creator...
My father passed it down to me.
Don't let my children and
grandchildren have this illness.
He had Kayı on his mind.
His children...
The battle we'll fight tomorrow.
Abdurrahman Gazi. Tell me
Will we ever see such a Bey again?
We won't, brother.
We won't see someone like my Bey.
But brother...
What is he doing inside?
He doesn't make any sound.
- Did he?
- Brother...
I'm fine.
Don't worry.
After Osman ambushes Nikola tomorrow,
he'll have a trick ready for sure.
He'll keep Flatyos as a backup.
Don't worry, my Bey.
We'll take all necessary precautions.
No. Listen.
If Flatyos is waiting to ambush,
Savcı and Gündüz will flank him.
Don't worry, my Bey.
Do your heart good.
Keep your eyes open.
- We will, my Bey.
- Thank you, my Bey.
My Bey. You should rest.
Come on. You should rest too.
- As your order.
- As you order, my Bey.
Bamsı.
Abdurrahman.
May you live long, my Valiants.
What have I done?
I can't stand it.
I can't stand seeing him
with someone else.
Bala...
You can't give him a child.
But I will!
You will see!
I will take him from you.
You'll see.
It's not wrong.
It's not wrong to love him.
Or want him.
It's not wrong.
Osman Bey!
What is it, Abdurrahman Gazi?
It's important. You've taken
your weapons for a battle.
But Ertuğrul Bey
doesn't want you to go.
What are you saying, Abdurrahman Gazi?
He doesn't want me to?
My brothers are going to a battle
with the ambush I've set up.
Do you want me to sit here?
- My Osman...
- What will they do without me?
As you know, I don't
question Ertuğrul Bey's orders.
He told me to inform you.
And I did.
What does he want me to do?
Did he tell you?
My Osman...
Ertuğrul Bey is waiting for you
at Halime Hatun's grave.
- Thank you, Abdurrahman Gazi.
- Thank you.
MashaAllah (praise be).
We are all coming from soil.
And the soil is going to end us.
But I think it will take Osman sooner.
What are you planning, Nicola?
Sometimes you get bored of being yourself.
For example, I am going to be a Turk today.
We are ready, Nicola.
Is this governor Nicola?
I think the only thing resembles to me is
my sculputre, which has to be done by me.
Do not forget that you are representing me
Why are you doing this?
What are you after, hah?
İnal Bey, I am thrilled
and can't control it.
Do you know who your daughter is going to
bring me to save you?
- Osman.
- Not possible!
My daughter wouldn't do that!
She loves you. I hope she does it, İnal
Bey, I hope she does.
- If not, both you and your daughter dies.
- You ignoble dog!
I smell death, Vladius.
Get in position.
I'll take revenge for you today, father.
- We are getting close to the battlefield.
- Big day, huh Savcı?
We are going to make those dogs pay
if Allah permits, brother.
Inshallah brother, Inshallah.
We are going on foot from here.
Alps, we are going to be silent
as death.
My Halime.
The light of my heart.
It's time.
I yearn for you.
A gazelle took me to you.
An angel took me to you.
Now, that angel will recouple us.
My angel.
My happiness, my woman.
We are going to walk together in
heaven.
You and I will be together forever.
All the pain is gone.
Eternity is the gift for our patience.
What a bliss to live with you.
I'll come to you when I die.
Look who is coming.
Our Dark Osman.
He is down at the mouth again.
He reproaches to me.
He asks me why I didn't let him fight.
Salaimun Aleikum
(May peace be upon you)
Alaikum Salam.
(And unto you peace)
They are getting close, sir.
Don't forget, we are going to kill them
before they got Nicola.
Yes sir.
They are coming.
Let's do it.
Our father was right, brother.
They set a trap before we arrive in
Nicola's place.
They are in the bush.
May our holy war be blessed, brother.
Etvallah (thank you)
Here we are in their base.
Infidel Nicola is also there.
You become happy when you see the infidel,
Bamsı Bey.
Bamsı Bey gets younger at the war time,
don't you know that, Göktuğ?
Sons, we are going to attack suddenly.
Ya Allah!
Allah is eternal!
İnal Bey, you Turks say war is full
of tricks.
But you know what is the real trick?
The trap in another trap.
Yeah, yeah.
Savcı Bey and Gündüz Bey.
We are trapped!
Attack! Attack!
- Allah is eternal!
- Allah is rightous!
War never stops for a Ghazi, son.
Nicole goes, someone else shows up.
War never ends.
However, Ertuğrul Ghazi is leaving.
May Allah give you a long life., my Bey.
This is our last private conversation.
Yes it is, Osman.
I love all three of you.
I don't discriminate you.
Because you are my sons.
But you have a special place.
You are going to success huge events.
You are going to get ahead of me.
Nobody can get ahead of you.
No one can, father.
You will!
If you can't get ahead of me, I won't
give my blessings to you1
You have been carrying Kayı Beys
like a lion...
since I started the war.
As long as that lion carries us...
we are going to destroy whoever we
encounter...
and make Turks the victorious ones!
But if you try to let that lion go...
he is going to kill all of us.
The war will never stop.
It will be greater, and it should be.
- This is my objective, my father.
- Here in front of your mother's grave...
you need to promise me.
I promise you, father.
I will protect our tradition.
I will secure the justice.
I will be compassionate to my people.
I will listen to them.
Kayıs state is going to be home for the
oppressed...
it is going to be a shelter for all the
Turks.
I promise you father.
Long live.
May Allah give you victories.
May your name carry on!
- My Father.
- Son.
My valiant father!
Father!
Father! Father!
I'll save you father.
You traitor!
Targun Hatun, trap!
Bamsı Bey, this is injustice!
two versus one.
You are crazy.
You are crazy, good.
Crazy governor.
You know what they say.
Crazy finds crazy.
Come here!
Damn it! Attack!
You are mine today, dog!
You are going to die today, Savcı!
Damn you!
I'll kill all of you!
I'm your end, dog!
We need him, brother, we need him.
I'm not done with him yet.
I promise you father.
I'll perform my mission.
I'll secure the injustice.
I promised to the Kayı.
I promised to Kayı Bey in front of the
grave of Kayı Hatun.
From now on, I can't break my promise.
This is a huge promise.
This is a heavy promise.
Heey, Karayel, who carries me
from place to place.
If I can't keep my promise...
Then I will only be a unnecessary load
for you.
Hey Karayel!
If I can't keep my promise...
don't carry me!
Don't be my friend!
Trample me under your iron horshoes!
I swear!
Let the world hear me!
Thanks to Allah, Ertuğrul Bey.
We get to see you again.
I needed to see you before I return
to dust.
So, the time has come.
Kayı Bey is taking a new voyage.
You are going to walk without
me from now on.
The passenger's will enlightens the way,
Ertuğrul Bey.
Who is going to enlighten our way
after you?
Who is going to take over your sword?
Who is going to take over your
noble aim?
You'll have hard times ahead.
You are going to need tough men
in times like this.
The circle tightens.
In order for this circle to break, you
are going to need a man...
who is ready for clashes, whose aim
is only to be victorious...
who can do anything for the
future of his community.
Who has the gift, the intelligence?
Who is going to do politics for
the new Turkish state?
Who is going to create a new market
for the merchants of this country?
Who is going to lead Ahis?
Bey, he is the one to clear the way
to the horizon...
he is the one who goes in front...
he is the one who will pave the
way for Kayı.
He is my son, Osman.
He will conquer, he will rule in justice!
He will show you the way.
He is going to create a new state.
May Allah praise your decision.
We believe in Osman and his dawah.
Osman is going to found the state
Turks have been waiting for.
Our children are going to call that
state by his name!
This voyage that goes
From Aleppo to Sögüt...
is going to spread on Bursa, then İcle...
and then to the other side!
He put his hand on mine one night.
He talked about the other side, hoping
that I could hear.
He told me to carry on my name
to overseas.
I realized that he is the heir.
He was the only one among
my children who talked about seas...
...who was able to take
the boundaries of the Kayı...
...to offshores.
Ertuğrul Bey, we are as great as
our dreams and efforts.
Hail the Kayıs who make the Turks
dream of a state...
...in these difficult times.
Hail the ones who await...
...who point the far afield
in these difficult times...
...the infinite and holy state
that all Turks pay homage to.
Ertuğrul Bey!
Where is the target of the campaign?
To Allah, who is the owner
of the realms.
The secret is revealed!
O' Osman son of Ertuğrul Ghazi!
Are you ready?
O' son of the Bey!
Are you ready for the great jihad?
O' the one who speaks the
truth in the name of Allah...
...tell me.
Our prophet told the ones who returned
from jihad...
...''Hail the ones who finished the little jihad,
the ones who'll have the great jihad forever''
Osman Bey...
...you know the little jihad.
Do you know the great jihad?
Isn't great jihad the jihad against
our own desires?
It is, son of the bey.
It is.
But who is powerful enough
for this jihad?
They don't discriminate among the
creatures that Allah created...
...they don't make decisions before
seeing through things...
...they don't call themselves victorious
before beating their desires.
O' the one who speaks the truth
in the name of Allah!
Tell me, is a son of a bey strong
enough for this jihad?
Allah offered the escrow to mountains...
...they didn't accept.
Humans are cruel and ignorant.
They accepted it.
Now it's our responsibility to carry
it and remember that it's an escrow.
Don't think it's yours.
In this world that you are a guest,
don't say that you are an owner.
This is your jihad.
The only owner is Allah, forever.
Even if I lose this idea
for a day...
...come again and remind me again.
This is our job.
Godspeed.
He will choose one of his sons.
He didn't even consider me.
In front of all the beys, he'll either
say Osman's or Savcı's name.
The name that Ertuğrul Ghazi will
say...
...will be an order for all the beys.
You made your plans
based on Ertuğrul Bey's death...
...but he resurrected.
To ruin everything, he resurrected.
Dündar Bey...
Dündar, you should do something.
Ertuğrul must die before...
...saying that name.
What are you saying, woman?
Neither Ertuğrul, Savcı nor Osman
are of my concern!
If you aren't going to
be the bey...
...neither your tents nor your
future is of my concern!
Because if you can't be the bey,
neither Savcı nor Osman will let us live.
Understand that!
They tried to hide behind the bushes.
They think they know the woods better we do.
Mashallah, mashallah to my valiants.
We have beaten the heathens.
It would be good to hit Nikola
like we hit Flatyos.
His time will come,
his time will come.
Our brother took his castle and
we ripped his right hand.
I would've liked to come.
I would want to chain Nikola.
-But...
-But my father had to talk to you.
Yes, brother.
We visited my mother's grave.
-May Allah bless her.
What were you doing there?
-He wanted me to give a promise.
-What is that promise?
He told me to protect the tents.
Don't worry, both of you.
The tents are in safe hands.
It is, it is. It is.
It is in safe hands.
But now leave these aside.
Ertuğrul Bey is gathering a great meeting.
All the beys are invited.
You should be ready too.
Come on.
Brothers.
Maybe...
...this is the last meeting
of our father.
Beware, don't do something
that will upset him.
This is a day of victory,
We should go to my father victorious.
We'll, brother.
We'll.
Mashallah. Mashallah.
He lost too much blood. Go to the castle
and let them know that Nikola is well.
Alps are searching everywhere for him.
We can't allow that.
Go now.
Nikola, it's me...
Nikola, Nikola...
Nikola you were killing me.
I saved you from the alps
and brought you here.
-You lost too much blood.
-I need to go to the castle.
-No, no, no!
-I must go to the castle!
Rome doesn't...
Rome doesn't lose!
You lost too much blood.
You can't go.
You are the last hope of our empire.
-The castle, don't go to the castle.
-All right, Nikola.
All right, all right, all right.
Hang on.
We can't lose...
I don't lose, Rome doesn't lose...
Rome doesn't lose, Rome can't lose...
Flatyos...
Flatyos the lion hunter.
I wish they had left you to me.
I wish they had left you over
to me.
I would make you pay for the things you
did. The things you had done to Ayaz!
Untie me and see me making
you regret your words, Göktuğ.
Göktuğ Alp! Wait.
I have more quarrel with the heathen.
Open it.
Savcı.
Your father killed my father.
I will avenge him.
Sooner or later.
The day that I take your wife...
...my Lena...
...that day will be my revenge.
You won't speak of my wife's name.
This is what will I do to Nikola who holds
your leashes. I'll hang him.
Göktuğ Alp!
Watch this dog carefully.
He shouldn't die. He'll be hung.
With the name of Allah.
Allah who creates,
who puts faith into our hearts...
...with Allah's ninety-nine names...
My children, I congratulate your victory.
May Allah destine you and our
tents with many victories.
Amin! Amin!
These lands are conquered with the
blood and effort of the ghazis.
The ones who jihaded in
the name of Allah...
...gained the blessing of Allah.
The ones left from
those Ghazis are...
...Bamsı Bey and
Abdurrahman Ghazi.
They are my will for you.
Respect them as you respect me.
My children, my beys...
...I, Ertuğrul Ghazi son of Süleyman Shah.
I'm about to hand over my escrow
that is my life.
These are my last words
and...
...my last advices.
Open your ears and listen to me well.
A state is the will of the people
that creates it...
...and their...
...consent.
It's a place that protects...
...the dignity and freedom
of the people.
And for a Turk, the state is one more
thing than those things...
It's an idea. That idea is protecting
all the oppressed...
...regardless of their languages
or their religions...
...against all the tyrants...
...ruling with justice and
making the laws live.
The eyes of the oppressed are on us...
...their prayers are with you.
If you bow down to slavery...
...and see a tyrant state as legitimite,
whether it's Rum or Mongol...
...how can the prayers of the oppressed
be true?
How can justice be served?
How can the laws live on?
Whatever the price is, break the
chains of slavery.
The flag of Kayıs can't bow down...
...to any power except Allah's.
Wherever the heathens gather...
...an army...
...the flag of Kayı...
...and it's the noble Alps should stand.
Those who don't believe in Allah's
victory...
...deny the truth.
First, be good muslims.
Then, get ready for jihad.
You'll see...
...the victory will be yours.
What you do is also jihad.
If artisans and merchants
don't work right...
...if they don't produce with
the sense of jihad...
...the efforts of the Ghazis
will go in vain.
The state can't grow.
Every morning when
you get to work...
...say that you are in jihad then.
So, be like Davud Bey.
Thank you, my bey.
O' Kayıs...
...do you think that I did my job right?
We do, my bey.
O' Kayıs...
...do you give
me your blessings?
We do, my bey!
Now, if I announce
my heir to you...
Will you respect him like you
respect me...
...and follow all his orders?
-We'll, my bey!
We'll, my bey!
My heir is...
I declare with peace in my heart...
...that he will take my place...
...the new Bey of Kayı...
...is the one who never lets the
fire of jihad extinguish...
...who carries the flag of Kayı
from one victory to another...
...who doesn't accept slavery
or any chain...
...my son...
-My bey!
-Father! Father!
Father!
Father! Father!
-Father!
-My bey...
I bear witness that there is no god
but Allah...
...and I bear witness that Muhammad
is the servant and Messenger of Allah
Father! Father!
Father!
-Father!
-Father...
My bey...
Wait, father!
Father!
My bey is gone,
he is gone...
He is gone!
My bey...
Bamsı Bey...
-Brother...
-Father!
My valiant father!
My dear father...
My Ghazi father...
-Brother...
No, no, no!
No, no! No!
Brother!
Gündüz Bey!
Gündüz Bey.
Brother...
Father...
My father...
Bamsı Bey...
Brothers...
Our father is dead.
Our father is dead...
Brother...
From now on...
we have a brother.
I'd die for you.
My Bey is gone.
"Peace and prayer be upon You...
O Messenger of Allah...
peace and prayer be upon You...
O loved by Allah...
O Prophet of Allah...
peace and prayer be upon You...
"O the Leader of past and future."
"Your Allah, the Almighty and the Glorious,
has the glory above all of the men."
"Peace be upon You, O Prophets...
Praises are only to Allah, the Lord,
creator, teacher and tamer of the realms."
[Surah Az-Zumar - 39:1]
Our Bey died!
- Our Ertuğrul Bey died!
- What are you saying, son?
Our Ertuğrul Bey died!
Died?
He's dead.
I couldn't take your revenge, father.
Ertuğrul died himself.
Forgive me. I promise you...
I'll cause his family to die.
I'll kill everyone who is his blood and
lay their bodies together.
I promise.
"Bismillah-ir-Rahman-ir-Rahim. (in the
name of Allah, the merciful and compassionate)
Yâ-Sĩn.
By the Quran, rich in wisdom!
You ˹O Prophet˺ are truly
one of the messengers...
upon the Straight Path.
This is a revelation from the
Almighty, Most Merciful...
so that you may warn a people...
whose forefathers were
not warned, and so are heedless.
The decree ˹of torment˺ has
already been justified...
against most of them, for they will
never believe.
˹It is as if˺ We have put shackles...
around their necks up to their chins...
so their heads are forced up,
and have placed a barrier before them...
and a barrier behind them...
and covered them ˹all˺ up, so they fail
to see ˹the truth˺."
"Verily we belong to Allah, and verily to
Him do we return."
My Allah, accept the big
Ghazi to your heaven.
"So glory be to the One in Whose Hands
is the authority over all things...
and to Whom ˹alone˺ you will
˹all˺ be returned."
"Allah Almighty speaks the truth.”
"Your Allah, the Almighty and the Glorious,
has the glory above all of the men.
Peace be upon You, O Prophets...
Praises are only to Allah, the Lord,
creator, teacher and tamer of the realms. Al- Fatihah.
- May Allah be upon you.
- Thank you.
Every time before he slept..
he would pray.
He'd get angry with me when
I pray with a mistake.
Yes.
He wanted me to be
alim. ( Islamic scholar.)
Yes, he did.
You used to read so much.
He'd ask you questions...
then he'd be proud of you.
We are still proud of you.
However...
he loved you the most.
He called you "Kara Osmanım."
I love you too.
You do.
You do, brother.
My brother.
My brothers.
Sons.
You tore my heart out.
However...
I wish...
you said these words...
when our Bey was alive.
I wish...
We were nearly of the same age...
however...
we were ignorant, he was wise.
We were reckless...
he was brave.
We were lavish...
he was generous.
We were angry, he was wrathful.
He was born to be a Bey.
The happiness that
my Allah gave to the Turk Beys...
was glowing in him.
My Bey...
My Ertuğrul Bey...
Selcan Mother.
Tell us about Ertuğrul Ghazi.
How?
Words aren't enough to tell about
such a Bey.
Words aren't enough.
My Bey...
he was light.
During the peace, he was
understanding and merciful.
During the war, he was like a lion.
Before and after he was Bey, he couldn't
have a moment of peace.
Firstly, for Kayı and then us.
He tried hard.
I was young and ignorant.
I caused him trouble.
May Allah forgive me.
I hope he gave me his blessings Inshallah.
He did.
Selcan Mother.
You became a
mother to his motherless children.
I did.
You even raised your brides
like your daughters.
We're grateful to you.
- So is Ertuğrul Bey.
- Inshallah.
He gave his blessings so that he
entrusted Osman to you.
He did.
- You are my mother, from now on.
- I'd die for you.
My Gonca.
My beautiful daughter.
You're my daughter too.
Come here.
I'm your mother too
My heart hurts.
My father.
My valiant father.
My brave father.
My Ghazi father.
I waited for you.
I waited for you to come.
You came.
You came but...
you were sick.
You were so sick.
You hurt my heart.
Father.
My dear father.
My father...
How will we be worthy of you?
How will we thank you enough?
Tell me.
My Osman.
My Osman. I'd die for you.
I'd die for your tears.
It'll be a good funeral.
Don't worry.
My Sheikh's followers are coming too.
May Allah give them a long life.
Allah...
took his loved man.
My Bala...
we should be patient.
Of course, my Osman.
Patience is what is true to the Muslim.
If you want to talk, I'm here.
I know, my Bala.
I know.
From now on...
from now on...
it's time to do the hardest thing.
Abdurrahman Ghazi.
Son.
He's gone, the Bey of Kayıs is gone.
Ghazi of the Ghazis is gone.
- Allahu Akbar! (Allah is the greatest!)
La ilaha illallah!
(There is no deity but Allah!)
- Allahu Akbar! (Allah is the greatest!)
None of us will be sad...
for our Bey is dead.
Every one of us will be Ertuğrul Ghazi.
We'll look at Kayı's matter like him!
We'll go on this way with
his faith.
Sons...
Ertuğrul Ghazi is dead.
He'll be taken to the Lord of the realms.
However, he left you something.
He left you the
dawah of righteousness...
that he had brought to you over mountains,
that he protected at the cost of his life...
that he gave it to you here in Söğüt
to carry it on.
The seed of a great state...
is the good news of a great state.
Protect it.
Protect it!
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com